<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FP16 | Liyuan Liu</title>
    <link>https://liyuanlucasliu.github.io/tags/fp16/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://liyuanlucasliu.github.io/tags/fp16/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>FP16</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © Liyuan Liu</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://liyuanlucasliu.github.io/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>FP16</title>
      <link>https://liyuanlucasliu.github.io/tags/fp16/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>FP16 and Apex</title>
      <link>https://liyuanlucasliu.github.io/blog/2020-03-fp16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liyuanlucasliu.github.io/blog/2020-03-fp16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For recent Nvidia GPUs like V100 or R8000, allowing half-precision training can get roughly 2X speedup instantly, and the only problem is &lt;strong&gt;how to conduct mixed-precision training?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike TPU, typical Nvidia GPUs follow the IEEE fp16 standard instead of bfp16.
Specifically, TPU uses the bfp16 standard with 8 exponent bits and 7 mantissa bits, while fp16 has only 5 exponent bits and 10 mantissa bits.
With less exponent bits, directly applying half-precision to deep learning leads to tons of overflow and underflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To compensate the loss of exponent bits, dynamic loss scaling and mixed-precision training have been proposed.
The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pytorch/fairseq&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;fairseq&lt;/a&gt; package comes with naive fp16 support, and for custom models and other PyTorch codebases, the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/NVIDIA/apex/tree/master/apex&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Apex&lt;/a&gt; package is usually the go-to choice.
Besides 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://nvidia.github.io/apex/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the apex documentation&lt;/a&gt;, below provides some tips for mixed-precision training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dynamic-loss-scaling&#34;&gt;Dynamic Loss Scaling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DL.
Since it is easier to detect overflow then under, a minimal loss scale is recommended to set (e.g., 0.03125) and a small window helps to stabilize the training (e.g., 256).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike underflow, the overflow can be easily detected.
Accordingly, it is strategically benefical to make the model overflow to avoid underflow.
Specifically, &lt;strong&gt;loss scaling&lt;/strong&gt; is proposed to first scale-up the loss and gradients by a constant, then divide the gradient by the same constant after back-propagation.
Still, the choice of the constant is an open problem.
&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic loss scaling&lt;/strong&gt; is leveraged to dynamically update this constant during training.
Specifically, it starts from setting the constant to a large value, then halve its value when an overflow occurs, which indicates the constant value is probably too large.
Also, if no overflow is detected in N continuous updates which indicates the constant could be larger, it duplicates the constant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mixed-precision-training&#34;&gt;Mixed Precision Training&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DL.
Elementwise_affine parameters are easier to overflow and it is helpful to cast this part to fp32.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;others&#34;&gt;Others&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In apex, &lt;code&gt;opt_level&lt;/code&gt; can be set to &lt;code&gt;O0&lt;/code&gt; (full fp32), &lt;code&gt;O1&lt;/code&gt; (mixed precision), &lt;code&gt;O2&lt;/code&gt; (almost fp16), and &lt;code&gt;O3&lt;/code&gt; (full fp16).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To specifically cast a model to fp32:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;set model parameters, e.g.,
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;for n, p in model.named_parameters():
    if any([ki in n for ki in fp32_keys]):
        p.float()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cast precision conversion by monkey patching, e.g.,
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;orig_linear = torch.nn.functional.linear
def wrapped_linear(*args):
 casted_args = []
  for arg in args:
    if torch.is_tensor(arg) and torch.is_floating_point(arg):
      casted_args.append(arg.float())
    else:
      casted_args.append(arg)
  return orig_linear(*casted_args)
torch.nn.functional.linear = wrapped_linear
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
